# - - - - - - - - - AMIT KUMAR - - - - - - -

I'm graduate in bachelor of commerce from IGNOU, with work experience in a Corporate Company with decent position and currently exploring in web development. Having knowledge of CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, React.Js as well able to convert Figma, PSD files into React Components. I'm an efficient and hard-working professional who strongly believes in delivering productive and long-lasting results to the clients. Enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success.

#### PERSONAL DATA

ADDRESS: E-936 Saraswati Vihar, PitamPura New Delhi - 110034

PHONE: +91 8802665778

EMAIL: amit.agoffice@gmail.com
LINKEDIN: linkedin.com/in/amitaggarwal8

PORTFOLIO: http://amityyz.epizy.com GITHUB: https://github.com/tkamit6

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Current

React Js Developer at Digi Interact Pvt. Ltd.

DEC 2022 - CURRENT

- 1. In the initial phase, I engaged in the development of website pages through the utilization of HTML and CSS. Following this, I progressed to adopting React.js as my framework of choice.
- 2. Made custom pages using HTML CSS on WordPress.
- 3. Developed websites using React.Js, employing functional components for enhanced user experiences.

MAR 2019 - OCT 2022

Operation Executive at Setindiabiz

- 1. Work is to register different types of companies with license under Government. ie. Private Limited Company Registration.
- 2. Increased company profits through performance optimization strategies and efficiency improvements.
- 3. Built and strengthened relationships across functional leadership areas to keep revenue development and operational plans interconnected and effective.
- 4. Developed operational processes to help organization adapt to market change.

FEB 2021- FEB 2022

Formatter at IIT Bombay, Mumbai (work from home) *Document Formating* 

Did an Internship at IIT Bomaby at a post of documents formatters, Whre my work is to Re-edit old books Resize Font size, color, heading paragraph over open source web application Overleaf.

#### **PROJECTS**

Landing Page : React Based Landing Page. - Created CRUD tab using axios. Click Here.

React Js: React Js website. https://discoverthehunt.com/ React Js: React Js website. https://kamao.vercel.app/ Basic HTML: Simple HTML Web page using HTML, CSS Here

Book Store: Pronto Book Store Web page using HTML, CSS. prontobookstore.com/ React Js: Live Temprature App using Weather API. axios to post, put, get data,

Here

### **CERTIFICATION**

JUNE 2022 - Dec 2022 : MERN( React JS - Node JS - Mongo DB) - DUCAT, Delhi

## **EDUCATION**

DEC 2017 - 2020: Bachelor of Commerce,

Indira Gandhi Open University, Delhi

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

CSS, HTML, JAVASCRIPT, MONGO DB, GOOGLE SHEETS REACT.JS familiar with Elementor page builder,

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

DATE OF BIRTH: 21-06-1996

SEX: Male STATUS: Single NATIONALITY: Indian

STRENGTH: Optimistic, Punctuality, Hard Working